<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Changes</title>
    <author email="fgiust AT sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

	<release version="r8" date="in CVS" description="">
      <action dev="fgiust" type="update">
          Development is starting againg, with a new project admin and developer. The build system and documentation has been migrated to maven.
          Due to changes in directory structure, a new module in CVS has been created (tidy2): old files will left untouched and development will continue on this new module.
      </action>   
      <action dev="fgiust" type="remove">
          Packages org.w3c.dom and org.xml.sax have been removed from the distribution.
      </action>    
      <action dev="fgiust" type="add">
          Junit tests added to build process.
      </action>     
      <action dev="fgiust" type="fix">
          Fixed [610244]: NullPointerException in parsing bad html (Tidy crashes while trying to insert a node 
          into markup tree before element when parent is null). Thanks to Liam Quinn for the patch.
      </action>         
      <action dev="fgiust" type="add">
          Added german translation. Submitted by Paul Ebermann.
      </action>            
      <action dev="fgiust" type="add">
          Added spanish translation. Submitted by Senén de Diego.
      </action>              
      <action dev="fgiust" type="add">
          A JTidy ant task has been added: <code>org.w3c.tidy.ant.JTidyTask</code>. Donated to JTidy by Nikola Ken Barozzi.
      </action>      
      <action dev="fgiust" type="fix">
          Applied fix for Tidy test case [431716]: NullPointerException in generating slides.
      </action>         
      <action dev="fgiust" type="fix">
          Applied fix for Tidy test case [427675] Frameset followed by frame infinite loop.
      </action>          
      <action dev="fgiust" type="fix">
          Fixed jtidy [522003] Typo in Configuration.parseProps(): indent-attributes parameter ignored.
      </action>             
      <action dev="fgiust" type="fix">
          Fixed [427671] : LI w/FRAME/FRAMESET/OPTGROUP/OPTION loop.
      </action>           
      <action dev="fgiust" type="fix">
          Fixed [427840] : Span causes infinite loop.
      </action>           
      <action dev="fgiust" type="fix">
          Fixed [539369] Infinite loop %lt;/frame> after %lt;/frameset>
      </action>
    </release>
    
	<release version="04aug2000r7" date="August 1, 2001" description="">
      <action dev="" type="fix">
          TagTable is no longer a Singleton, which brings us one step closer
          to having the ability to run multiple JTidy's in a single JVM.
      </action> 
      <action dev="" type="fix">
          Tidy.java has been refactored and duplicate code has been removed.
      </action> 
      <action dev="" type="fix">
          The license is stated explicitly in the file LICENSE.
      </action>          
    </release>



	<release version="04aug2000r6" date="December 20, 2000" description="">
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Fixed a bug in the parseAttribute() method of Lexer.java which generated an incorrect
  length for the UTF8 representation of characters above \u007f.  This was causing
  a StringIndexOutOfBoundsException in method isValidAttributeName() of Lexer.java at
  line 2577.  Thanks to dlgo@users.sourceforge.net for reporting this problem.
      </action>
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Fixed a bug in the insertedToken() method of Lexer.java which generated a Negative
  ArraySizeException in the clone() method of Node.java.  An ending value for a range in
  a character array was not being set correctly.  Thanks again to
  dlgo@users.sourceforge.net for reporting this problem.
      </action>
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Fixed a bug in Lexer.java where a "!" was omitted from an if condition, causing 
  the reverse of expected behavior with namespaces.  Fix is attributed to Randi Waki
      </action>
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      dlp@users.sourceforge.net contributed a fix so that hasAttributes() in DOMNodeImpl.java
  would return the correct boolean value instead of throwing a not implemented exception.
      </action>
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Added support for CDATASections in the DOM model.
      </action>
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Fixed a bug in the createProps() method of Clean.java which caused a
  StringOutOfBoundsException in line 156 due to trailing spaces in a CSS property name.
      </action>
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Changed the behavior of DOMNodeImpl so that nodes added via the DOM interface have
  the correct node type.  Previously, such nodes could not contain any content because
  they were added with a type of StartEndTag.
      </action>
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Added methods to support DOM Level 2.
      </action>
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Fixed a bug where createElement() was not properly setting Node.tag if the tag to be added
  could not be found in the the TagTable.  A generic entry is now used instead of leaving the
  entry set to null.
      </action>
    </release>



	<release version="04aug2000r5" date="November 3, 2000" description="">
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      The getValue() method in DOMAttrImpl.java returns the attribute name 
  if the attribute value is null (thanks to Brett Knights for
  reporting this)
      </action>      
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Initial implementation of a Windows .bat file to drive the build process has 
  been added (thanks, Gary).
      </action>      
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      Compiled .class files are not included in the distribution as they
are already contained in the jar file.
      </action>         
    </release>

	<release version="04aug2000r4" date="November 1, 2000" description="">
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      The 04aug2000r4 release fixes the bugs reported since r3. Thanks
to Gary for implementing these changes.
      </action>
    </release>

	<release version="04aug2000r3" date="October 22, 2000" description="">
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      This release fixes a bug in the pre-compiled Tidy JAR. The messages property file is now included. No code changes. 
      </action>         
    </release>

	<release version="04aug2000r2" date="October 20, 2000" description="First SourceForge release of JTidy, packaged by 
Sami Lempinen.">      
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      The package structure has been reorganised a little. In the binary 
  release, the Java bytecode classes and the Tidy JAR can be found under
  the build/ subdirectory.

      </action>         
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      The Ant build system is now the authoritative one. The old Makefiles
  (untouched) can be found under contrib/ should someone want to start
  maintaining them.

      </action>         
      <action dev="" type="fix">
      A patch by Brett Knights has been incorporated. The patch affects
  the DOMNodeImpl class and ensures that CharacterData always returns
  at least an empty string (compared to null) as the value. This patch
  has not been verified with a DOM guru, so comments are welcome.

      </action>       
    </release>





  </body>
</document>
