<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>JTidy home</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="About JTidy">
            <p>
                JTidy is a Java port of
                <a href="http://www.w3.org/People/Raggett/tidy/">HTML Tidy</a>
                , a HTML syntax checker and pretty printer. Like its non-Java cousin, JTidy can be used as a tool for
                cleaning up malformed and faulty HTML. In addition, JTidy provides a DOM interface to the document that
                is being processed, which effectively makes you able to use JTidy as a DOM parser for real-world HTML.
            </p>
            <p>
                JTidy was written by Andy Quick, who later stepped down from the maintainer position. Now JTidy is
                maintained by a group of volunteers.
            </p>
            <p>
                More information on JTidy can be found on the
                <a href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/jtidy/">JTidy SourceForge project page</a>
                .
            </p>
        </section>
        <section name="News">
            <subsection name="November, 2004">
                <p>
                    New subproject:
                    <a href="multiproject/jtidyservlet">jtidyservlet</a>
                </p>
                <p>
                    The JTidy Servlet library is an open source suite of custom tags and servlets that integrate JTidy
                    HTML syntax checker and pretty printer functionality into Servlet/JSP container.
                </p>
                <p>JTidyservlet is managed by Vlad Skarzhevskyy, who recently joined the JTidy project.</p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="September 13, 2004">
                <p>Two major new features expected for the next release have been finally committed to cvs!</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        You can now use
                        <strong>any supported Java character encoding for input or output</strong>
                        , with the classic tidy encoding hadling replaced by a new implementation that take advantage of
                        built-in java character encoding support.
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        You don't need anymore to parse a text output to extract JTidy messages in your application: you
                        can simply attach a
                        <strong>
                            listener using
                            <code>Tidy.setMessageListener()</code>
                        </strong>
                        and be notified for error, warnings and summary messages.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>What is missing before a release?</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Cleanup the support for new charsets (still to be refined)</li>
                    <li>Doctype handling (seem to be really different from the current tidy c release)</li>
                    <li>Some more tests, expecially for the dom parser/prettyprinter</li>
                    <li>A working ant task and command line interface</li>
                </ul>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="August 20, 2004">
                <p>
                    More than 50% of the tests are now working, and hundreds of fixes and new features have been ported
                    from the c version. Xml/xhtml output is now fairly more robust. Check out a
                    <a href="nightly/">nightly build</a>
                    and reports any bug found!
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="March 12, 2004">
                <p>
                    Nightly builds are now automatically generated daily and the whole website is refresh at the same
                    time. 1/3 of the implemented tests is working now. Two years of reported bugs are difficult to catch
                    up, but the
                    <a href="changes-report.html">change log</a>
                    starts becoming "important"...
                </p>
                <p>
                    Do you wanna play with a recent build? Get the source or binary distribution from the
                    <a href="nightly/">nightly builds page</a>
                    .
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="January 21, 2004">
                <p>
                    Site updated using the latest maven version: test report is a lot more readable now (formatting has
                    been fixed in the latest junit-report plugin)... new site layout (using a tweaked version of the
                    maven xdoc plugin: xhtml + tableless CSS)
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="January 16, 2004">
                <p>
                    <strong>183</strong>
                    test cases fully implemented now. All the test cases from Tidy and some new tests for JTidy have
                    been added.
                </p>
                <p>
                    All the test cases which caused JTidy to crash or loop have been fixed! Priority (1) is done, now
                    there are other 139 tests failing. Note most of the test are failing at the firsts lines for
                    differences in doctype handling and formatting in Tidy (the latest Tidy release has been used to
                    produce output files for comparison).
                </p>
                <p>These are the priorities before a release:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Doctype handling (needed for tests)</li>
                    <li>Formatting (needed for tests)</li>
                    <li>
                        Xml output: making Jtidy always produce valid xml (the well known "duplicate attributes" bug)
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    Mh, formatting in maven-generated
                    <a href="junit-report.html">junit report</a>
                    is really bad, I just submitted a bug report to maven: error messages are escaped two times,
                    newlines are not preserved and random whitespaces are added. I think I should spend some time in
                    fixing junit report plugin bugs if I want to be able to fix JTidy bugs...
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="January 8, 2004">
                <p>
                    <strong>179</strong>
                    test cases for JTidy have been
                    <em>partially</em>
                    implemented and added!
                </p>
                <p>
                    All the test cases for the non java version of Tidy have been integrated.
                    <em>Partially</em>
                    because most of them don't check yet output or warnings produced by Tidy, but simply test that JTidy
                    doesn't crash or loop.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Well, actually as you can see in the
                    <a href="junit-report.html">junit report</a>
                    we have 1 test causing a NPE and 4 causing infinite loops! These bugs will have the precedence over
                    any incorrect output bug (fixing these will probably worth a new release, you don't want your
                    software to hang using JTidy, right?).
                </p>
                <p>
                    Anyway, in the TidyCrashingBugsTest (test that crashed the c version of Tidy) 21 of the 24 tests
                    works without problems... not so bad as expected.
                </p>
                <p>
                    See
                    <a href="testcases.html">testcases</a>
                    , if you wanna help JTidy supplying tests or fixes.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Thanks to the Clover team for the free license for the JTidy project!
                    <a href="http://www.thecortex.net/clover">
                        <img src="http://www.thecortex.net/clover/images/clovered1.gif" width="89" height="33"
                            alt="Code Coverage by Clover" />
                    </a>
                </p>
            </subsection>
            <subsection name="January 6, 2004">
                <p>JTidy new website is online!</p>
                <p>
                    The project is starting again after two years without a release. I (Fabrizio Giustina) just joined
                    the project as new administrator and developer.
                </p>
                <p>Main targets are now:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>migrate to maven as a build system (done)</li>
                    <li>
                        old code cleanup: remove unused code, clean up everything with the help of
                        <a href="checkstyle-report.html">checkstyle</a>
                        and
                        <a href="pmd-report.html">pmd</a>
                        , and update code to use new
                        <a href="coding_conventions.html">coding conventions</a>
                        .
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        add junit test coverage (started, see
                        <a href="junit-report.html">junit report</a>
                        and
                        <a href="clover/index.html">clover report</a>
                        ). I'm trying to integrate all the standard tidy testcases to check that jtidy will behave like
                        its non-Java cousin
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        Finally: integrate all the patches supplied by users in these years and the fixes in the
                        non-Java version
                    </li>
                </ul>
                <p>
                    A note about mailing lists: there are two new mailing list, specific to jtidy, see
                    <a href="mail-lists.html">project mailing lists</a>
                    . You can find previous discussions in
                    <a href="http://lists.w3.org/Archives/Public/html-tidy">html-tidy@w3.org</a>
                    archives (common to tidy and jtidy).
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>
