<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
    <properties>
        <title>JTidy how to</title>
        <author email="fgiust(at)users.sourceforge.net">Fabrizio Giustina</author>
    </properties>
    <body>
        <section name="How to">
            <p>You can use JTidy as an html checker/prettyprinter or as a DOM parser.</p>
            <p>
                First of all, you will need to
                <a href="download.html">download</a>
                a JTidy distribution. Inside it you will find a
                <code>jtidy-<em>{version}</em>.jar</code>, where
                <code>{version}</code>
                is the JTidy release number: this is the jar containing all the JTidy classes you need, and we will name
                it this simply <code>jtidy.jar</code>
                in the following how to. No other libraries are needed.
            </p>
            <p>Now that you have JTidy you can use it in different ways.</p>

            <subsection name="JTidy executable">
                <p>
                    Run
                    <code>java -jar jtidy.jar {options}</code>
                    to access JTidy command line interface.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <code>java -jar jtidy.jar -h</code>
                    will output a short help on jtidy command line with a few examples.
                </p>
                <p>
                    <code>java -jar jtidy.jar -help-config</code>
                    will output all the available configuration options and
                    <code>java -jar jtidy.jar -show-config</code>
                    the current (default) values. .
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Ant task">
                <p>
                    Detailed instructions on how to use the JTidy ant task can be found in
                    <a href="apidocs/org/w3c/tidy/ant/JTidyTask.html">JTidyTask javadocs</a>.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="JTidy API">
                <p>
                    The entry point for accessing JTidy functionalities is the
                    <code>org.w3c.tidy.Tidy</code>
                    class. This is a simple example of use:
                </p>
                <pre>
                    <![CDATA[
Tidy tidy = new Tidy(); // obtain a new Tidy instance
tidy.setXHTML(boolean xhtml); // set desired config options using tidy setters 
...                           // (equivalent to command line options)

tidy.parse(inputStream, System.out); // run tidy, providing an input and output stream
]]>
                </pre>
                <p>
                    Using
                    <code>parseDOM(java.io.InputStream in, java.io.OutputStream out)</code>
                    instead of
                    <code>parse()</code>
                    you will also obtain a DOM document you can parse and print out later using
                    <code>pprint(org.w3c.dom.Document doc, java.io.OutputStream out)</code>
                    (note that the JTidy DOM implementation is not fully-featured, and many DOM methods are not
                    supported).
                </p>
                <p>
                    Starting from release r8, JTidy also provide a MessageListener interface you can implement to be
                    notified for warning and errors in your html code. For details on advanced uses refer to jtidy
                    javadocs.
                </p>

            </subsection>

        </section>
    </body>
</document>

